Guide to the Leander E. Keck Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Writings, Series II
  - Papers and Articles
    - "Acts: A Portrait of First Generation Christians" in Adult Leader, 1973 March (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - "Sexuality in the New Testament" in The Junction, Vol. 8, No. 3 Spring, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - "Listening To and Listening For: From Text to Sermon (Acts 1:8)" from Interpretation, Vol XXVII, No 2, 1973 April (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - "The Son Who Creates Freedom" in Concilium, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - "The Son Who Creates Freedom" Concilium in French, German, Spanish, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - "On the Ethos of Early Christians" - Reprint from Journal of the American Academy of Religion, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Publications in Baptist Leader, Bethany Guide and Candler Review, 1974-1978 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Articles in Interpreter's Dictionary of the Bible, 1975 April (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - A Response to Gager, "The Gospels and Jesus, Some Doubts and Method" in Journal of Religion, Vol. 54, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Response to Farmer: "The Post-sectarian Character of Matthew", 1975 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - "Priorities for Theological Education", Lexington Theological Quarterly, Vol X, No. 1; "The Presence of God Through Scriptures", Lexington Theological Quarterly, Vol X, No. 3, 1975 January, July (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - "Texts and Traditions Associated with Antioch: Rudiments of a Very Preliminary Report" - John Brunt and L.E. Keck, 1975 October (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - "Reflections on Declining Church Membership" in Occasional Papers, Vol 1, No. 4; "Apocalypse and Ecclesia", 1975 October 25 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - "The Historical Jesus and Christology" for Perkins Journal, Southern Methodist University, 1975-1976 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - "Justification of the Ungodly and Ethics" in Rechtfertigung, Festschrift Fur Ernst Kasemann, Zum 70. Geburtstag, Mohr Siebeck, Tübingen, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - "New Patterns of Worship: A Conversation" in the Candler Review, 1976 January (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Theologische Realenzyklopadie "Armut, N.T." / Poverty in the NT, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - "Response to David Robertson's The Old Testament and the Literary Critic" - SBL Annual Meeting, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - "The New Testament Experience of Faith", 1977-1978 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - "Ethos and Ethics in the New Testament: Mostly Preliminary Remarks" for College Theological Society, 1978 January (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - "Are the Gospels Biographies?" in The New Review of Books and Religion, Volume II, Number 9, 1978 May (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - "The Law and 'The Law of Sin and Death' (Rom. 8:1-4): Reflections on the Spirit and Ethics in Paul" for the Silberman festschrift, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - "The Post-Pauline Interpretation of Jesus' Death in Rom 5,6-7" in Theologia Crucis-Signum Crucis in Festschrift fur Erich Dinkler zum 70. Geburtstag, Mohr Siebeck, Tübingen, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - "Remarks Preliminary to Reflections on the Papers"; "Historicky Jezis a Evangelium," Miscelanea (Prague), 79-107., 1979 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Papers from the Workshop on Theological Education, 1979 October 12-13 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - "The Possibility of Biblical Theology" - Rocky Mt. SBL, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - "Pauline Theology in New Testament Criticism"; "Jesus in New Testament Christology" (Oct 1980), 1980 October (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - "Scripture as Integrator of Theological Education for Ministry" APEM Denver, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - "Is the New Testament a Field of Study? or, From Outler to Overbeck and Back" - Address given at TCU in 1980, turned into an article in The Second Century (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - "Scripture and Canon" - This essay is an edited version of a convocation address delivered at Union Theological Seminary in Richmond, Va, 1981 September 9 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - "Toward a Theology of Rhetoric/Preaching" - from conference on Theology and Practice, Univ. of Chicago - published in Practical Theology, by D. Browning, Harper, 1983, 1982 October 27 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - "What Ever Happened to Thinking?" in The Association of Theological Schools in the United States and Canada (ATS Notes); "Babel and Beyond," Theological Education, 1984 Autumn, pp. 34-48, 1983 December/ 1984 January, Autumn (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - "Ethics in the Gospel According to Matthew", 1983/1984 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - "Jesus in the New Testament Christology"; "The New Testament and Nicea: Mostly Preliminary Remarks," for ATS (1986); "Toward the Renewal of New Testament Christology," New Test. Stud. 32 (1986); "Romans 1:18-23" for Interpretation (1986 Oct), 1984, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - "Christology, Soteriology, and the Praise of God (Rom 15:7-13)" in The Conversation Continues: Essays on Paul and John Presented to J. Louis Martyn, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Reflections from the Dean and "From Where I Sit"; "Research and Development in Theological Education: Some Farewell Thoughts", 1988/1989 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - "Romans 15:4: An Interpolation?" in Faith and History: Essays in Honor of Paul W. Meyer, 1988-1990 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Draft of "From Where I Sit", 1989 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - "A Response to Biblical Preaching on the Death of Jesus" - SBL, Bible and Contemporary Theologies Group session, New Orleans, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - "The Logic of Paul's Soteriology" - SBL November 22, 2004 November 22 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - "Images of Paul in the New Testament"; "Meditation: Phil 1:3-11" (Random collection of papers) (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - "Paul and Apocalyptic Theology"; "Paul's Theology in Historical Criticism", no date (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - "The Spirit and the Dove" - New Testament Studies 17:41-67 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Gospel of Mark papers- "Mark 3:7-12 and Mark's Christology" JBL; "The Introduction to Mark's Gospel", New Testament Studies 12 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - "Romans 1:1-7: A Case Study in Exegesis"; "Memo Re: Rom. 1:3-4 in Critical Discussion"; "The Function of Rom. 3:10-18: Observations and Suggestions", "Romans 1:18-23. Expository Articles Interpretation" (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - "The Historical Jesus and Christology: The Problem" (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - "1 Thessalonians 2:14-16" (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - "God's Christ and His People" (Reprint) (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - "Jesus in Romans", no date (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Reviews of others' Books
    - Review of "Paul: The Theology of the Apostle in the Light of Jewish Religious History" by Hans Joachim Schoeps, Trans. Harold Knight, Westminster Press, 1961 in Union Seminary Quarterly Review, Vol. XVIII, No. 1, 1962 November (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Reviews of "Jesus and the Gospel" by Ernest C. Colwell and "The Pastoral Epistles" by C.K. Barrett in Foundations, 1963 October (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Review of "The Cambridge Bible Commentary on the New English Bible." Introductory Volume; "Understanding the New Testament", edited by Miss O. Jessie Lace; "The Gospel According to Mark" by C.F.D. Moule for Religion in Life, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Review of "The Essene Heritage" by Martin A. Larson, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Review of "Anchor Bible: The Acts of the Apostles" by Johannes Munck, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Review of "The Theme of Jewish Persecution of Christians in the Gospel According to St. Matthew" by Douglas R.A. Hare for Religion and Life, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Review of "The Parables" by Dan Otto Via, Jr. for Foundations, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Review of "Jesus in the Gospels" by Ernest W. Saunders, 1968 December (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Review of "St. Luke: Theologian of Redemptive History" by Helmut Flender for Journal of the American Academy of Religion, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Review of "John the Baptist in the Gospel Tradition" by Walter Wink, U.S.Q.R., 1968 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Review of "Jesus in the Church's Gospels: Modern Scholarship and Earliest Sources" by John Reuman, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Review of "An Introduction to the Theology of Rudolf Bultmann" by Walter Schmithals for Religion and Life, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Review of "Faith and Understanding" by Rudolf Bultmann for Religion in Life, 1969 July (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Review of "I Saw A New Earth: An Introduction to the Visions of the Apocalypse" by Paul S. Minear, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Review of "The Kingdom of God in the Synoptic Tradition" by Richard H. Hiers for Journal of the American Academy of Religion, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Review of "Jesus Means Freedom" by Ernst Kasemann for Journal of Biblical Literature Vol 90, no. 3, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Review of "New Testament Theology: The Proclamation of Jesus" by Joachim Jeremias for Interpretation, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Review of "The Love Command in the New Testament" by Victor Paul Furnish for The Review of Books and Religion, Vol 1, No. 10, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Review of "Die Taufe Jesu nach den Synotikern: Literarkritische und gattungsgeschichtliche Untersuchungen" by Frtzleo Lentzen-Deis, S.J. for Journal of Biblical Literature Vol 92, no. 4, 1973 Dec (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Review of "Eschatology and Ethics: Essays on the Theology and Ethics of the Kingdom of God" by Carl E. Braaten for Religion in Life, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Review of "Jesus the Jew: A Historian's Reading of the Gospel" by Geza Vermes, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Review of "The Identity of Jesus Christ: The Hermeneutical Bases of Dogmatic Theology" by Hans W. Frei, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Religious Studies Reviews, 1975-1980 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Review of "Ethics in the New Testament" by Jack T. Sanders, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Review of "The Passion in Mark: Studies in Mark 14-16" edited by Werner H. Kelber, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Review of "1 Corinthians" by W. F. Orr and J. A. Walther for Religion in Life, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Book Reviews, 1970-71, 1974, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Review of "The Origin and Destiny of Humanness: An Interpretation of the Gospel According to Matthew" by Herman C. Waetjen, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Review of "Can We Trust the New Testament?" by John A.T. Robinson, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Review of "A Marxist Looks at Jesus" by Milan Machovec for Journal of Biblical Literature, Vol 97, no.1, 1978 March (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Review of "What is a Gospel?: The Genre of the Canonical Gospels" by Charles H. Talbert for New Review of Books and Religion, 1978 May (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Review of "Semitism in the New Testament?" by Samuel Sandmel; "Anti-Judaism in Christian Theology" by Charlotte Klein; "Evangelicals and Jews in Conversation on Scripture, Theology and History" ed. by M.H. Tannenbaum, M.R. Wilson and A.J. Rudin for Interpretation, 1978 October (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Reviews, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Review of "What Are They Saying About the Social Setting of the New Testament?" by Carolyn Osiek, R.S.C.J. for St. Luke's Journal of Theology, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - Reviews of "Romans" by Paul Achtemeier and "Matthew and Paul: A Comparison of Ethical Perspectives" by Roger Mohrland in Interpretation, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - Review of "Bearing the Cross" by David J. Garrow, 1987 November 19 (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - Review of "From Jewish Prophet to Gentile God: The Origins and Development of New Testament Christology" by Maurice Casey for Interpretation, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - Review of "The Rhetoric of Righteousness in Romans 3: 21-26" by Douglas C. Campbell for Journal of Biblical Literature, 1992 October 30 (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - Review of "The Gospel According to St. Mark" by Morna D. Hooker, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Christology and History: A Review Essay", 1999 (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - "Is the Resumed Quest of The Historical Jesus New?" (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Others' reviews of Keck's work
    - Reviews of "Mandate to Witness", 60s-70s (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - Reviews of "Taking the Bible Seriously", 1962-1963 (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - Reviews of "Studies in Luke-Acts", etc, 1970-1971 (Box 10, Folder 44)
    - Reviews of "A Future for the Historical Jesus", 1971-1972 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Reviews of "The Bible in the Pulpit", 1978-1980 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Book Reviews, 1978-86 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Reviews of "Paul and His Letters" in Fortress, 1979-1981 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Reviews of "Studies in Luke-Acts", 1980-1981 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Reviews of "The Pauline Letters", 1986-1987 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Reviews of "Church Confident", 1993-94 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Reviews of "The New Interpreter's Bible", 1994 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Reviews of "Who is Jesus?: History in Perfect Tense", 2000 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Reviews of "Romans" ANTC. Nashville: Abingdon Press., 2005-06 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Misc. information on 11th Dean of Divinity School, 1878(?) (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Sound sheet interviews for high school course: "Why Romans?", 1969 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Issue of Breakthrough, 1970 October (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Interview- "What is Biblical Preaching?" with Wendell Willis, 1970 November (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - "Annual Report to the Dean" - Candler School of Theology, Emory University, 1973 June (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - "Being the Leaven and Not the Lump" in Adult Leader; "The Way to Biblical Preaching", Thesis Theological Cassettes - Update, Oct. 1977, 8/9, 1978 June-Aug; October 1977 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Chattanooga Trial, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - First Presbyterian Church bulletin, 1980 August (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Sydney Ahlstrom Funeral; In Memory of Roland Bainton, 1894-1984, Reflection, Nov 1984; In Memory of Robert L. Calhoun, 1896-1983, Reflection, Nov 1984, 1984 July 9, November (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - ATS Special Visiting Committee report, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Annual Report, The Divinity School, 1988-1989 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Minutes, Council on Theological Education, 1988 April 13-14 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Second Blue Ribbon Task Force, Dallas, TX, 1989 January 19-20 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - ATS related material, 1992-2008 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - E. Keck Bio. Sketches; Publications of Leander E. Keck (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Reflections on Curriculum (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Course-related Material, Series III
  - N.T. Seminar - Wellesley, 1958-59 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Galatians Exegesis, Fall 1959-1960 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - 310b: Exegesis of Romans, Faith of Paul, Vanderbilt, 1959-1960 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - 310b: Faith of Paul; Gal-Rom., Fall 1959-1960 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - 311: Life of Jesus, Fall 1960 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Colossians, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - N.T. Introduction - Synoptics, Unit III, A-B, Spring 1960 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Philippians, Spring 1960 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Rel 312: Deutero-Pauline Letters, Summer 1960 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Myth & De-Mythology, Summer 1960 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - The Life and Teachings of Jesus, Fall 1960-1961 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - 311: Life and Teachings of Jesus, Fall 1960-1961 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Faith of Paul - 2 Corinthians, Spring 1961 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Rel 310a: Faith of Paul - 2 Corinthians, Spring 1961 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - N.T. Seminar - Paul in Acts, Summer 1961 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Seminar in Practical Theology - Mark, 1961-1962 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - N.T. Seminar - Sermon on the Mount, Summer 1962 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - N.T. History and Literature, Spring 1962 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - English Exegesis - Acts 1-12, Summer 1962 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - New Testament History & Literature Culture Context, 1962-1963 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Keck-Tucker - Intro to the Bible, 1962-1967 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - N.T. Hist. & Lit., Spring 1963 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - 310b: The Faith of Paul - 1 Corinthians, Spring 1963 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Methods of Biblical Criticism, 1963-1964 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - New Testament History & Literature - Synoptics, 1963-1964 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Baptism of Jesus, Fall 1964 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - N.T. Seminar - Jesus & Pharisees, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Faith of Paul - Thess. & Phil., Summer 1964 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Faith of Paul 310 - Thessalonians, Philippians, Summer 1964 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - New Testament Introduction - Pauline Epistles, 1964-1967 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - 311: Studies in the Life & Teachings of Jesus, Fall 1965-1966 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Studies in the Life & Teachings of Jesus, 1965-1966 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - N.T. 235b - Hist & Lit., Spring 1966 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Rel. 300: Methods of Bibl. Crit., Spring 1966 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - N.T. Seminar 391b - The Quest of the Historical Jesus, Old & New, Spring 1966 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Canon and Criticism, 1966-1967 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Methodist Curriculum, Adult Teacher, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Psychology on Religion 439- Seminar on Death, Spring 1967 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - N.T. Seminar - Jewish & Early Christian Apocalyptic, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Rel. 396: Sem. in Christian Ethics - Sin & Forgiveness (w/ Laney), Fall 1968 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - 315: Fourth Gospel & Homily on Hist. Crit. Study of John, Spring 1968 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - 310: Romans, Fall 1968 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - N.T. Text Criticism, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - 311b: Sermon on the Mount, Fall 1969-1970 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - 307b: Pauline Interpretation of Christianity, Spring 1970 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - 382a: Revelations and Ethics with Sellers, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Pauline Interpretation of Christianity Syllabus, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Colloquium with P.C. Hodgson, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - N.T. 329 - Gospel of Mark, 1972 July 20-August 16 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Unity & Diversity of NT Notes, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Pauline Freedom - 1 Corinthians, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Problem of Biblical Authority, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Christology of the Lives of Jesus, 1972-1996 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Understanding of Man in N.T., Winter 1974 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - N.T. Ethics - Today Vanderbilt, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - NT 495: NT Apocrypha, Winter 1975 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - NT 301, Fall 1976 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - NT 495: NT Apocrypha, Fall 1977 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - NT. 307: Theology of Paul, Fall 1977 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - B 303: Crit. Intro., Winter 1977 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Apocalyptic Seminar, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - NT 345: Exegesis of Romans, Summer 1978 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - B 301, Fall 1978 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Jesus, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Tucker-Keck - Crit. Intro., Winter 1979 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Romans, Fall 1980 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Christology of N.T. Jesus in N.T. Christology, Spring 1980 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - English Exegesis of Romans, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Romans Seminar, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Greek Exegesis of Romans, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Centrum Paulinum SBL, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - English Exegesis of Romans, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - English Exegesis of Romans, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - The Christology of the N.T., 1984 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Paul and the Jews, 1985 January (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - English Exegesis of Romans, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - English Exegesis of Romans, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - English Exegesis of Romans, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - English Exegesis of Romans, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - 634b: Seminar on Luke-Acts, Spring 1991 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Syllabus for New Testament Interpretation: A Guide, 1991-1992 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - N.T. Interpretation, 1991-1992 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - N.T. Interpretation, 1992-1996 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - N.T. Interpretation (Cont'd), 1992-1996 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Gospel Making and its Results, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - NT Interpretation, Fall 1993, Fall 1994 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Romans (Greek), 1995 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Romans: Handouts, Fall 1995 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Syllabus for New Testament Interpretation: A Guide, Fall 1995 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Rel 669a: Christology in the lives of Jesus, Fall 1996 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Rel 601b: Syllabus for New Testament Interpretation, Yale Divinity School, Spring 1996 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Rel. 368a: English Exegesis of Romans, Fall 1997 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Romans, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Romans 13, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Rel 638a: English Exegesis of Romans, Fall 1997 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - English Exegesis of Paul's Letter for Roman Christians, Duke, 2002 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - N.T. 321: The Theology of Paul: Romans, Spring 2002 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Seminar notes (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Ephesians (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Romans 16, misc (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - The Jewishness of Jesus (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Jewishness of Jesus (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Jewish Christianity (Box 18, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, Series IV
  - Regarding lectures and speaking events
    - World Convention of Churches of Christ, Ninth Assembly, Mexico City, 1974 July 30-Aug 4 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Perkins School of Theology Lectures, 1978 February 6-9 (Box 18, Folder 12a)
    - Australia Trip, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Concordia College Summer Conference on Theology and Ministry, Concordia College, Moorehead, Minnesota, 1979 July 23-26 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Gray Lectures - Duke Divinity School, 1979 October 21-24 (Box 18, Folder 14a)
    - Public lectures at University of South Carolina, Columbia, S.C., 1980 March 18 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Commencement address at Atlanta Christian College - "Value and Person", 1980 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Linfield, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - 1980 Summer Seminar of the Eastern Pennsylvania Annual Conference and Wyoming Annual Conference, Albright College, Reading, PA, 1980 July 29- August 1 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - The Burlan A. Sizemore Jr. Memorial Lectureship in Biblical Studies, 1980 November 11-14 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Theology and Practice: Ecumenical Perspectives on Practical Theology, University of Chicago, 1981 January 8-9 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Clergy Seminar, Hiram College, Hiram, Ohio, 1981 May 6 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - C.M Chilton Lecturer at First Christian Church, Columbia, Missouri, 1981 February 3-5 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - The Thedford G. and Woodrow W. Sprinkle Lectures, "Paul and Preaching: Themes in Romans", Atlantic Christian College, Wilson, North Carolina, 1981 March 18-19 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Princeton Institute of Theology, 1981 June 29-July 9 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - First United Methodist Church, Shelton, CT, 1981 November 24 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Forty-seventh Annual Ministers' Week at Emory University, "Grace and Wholeness: The Inner Discipline of the Minister", 1982 January 11-13 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Sermon at Trinity Church, Princeton, 1982 January 24 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Bangor Theological Seminary Convocation, The 77th Annual Program, 1982 January 25-27 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Friends of Yale Divinity School, Yale Divinity School, 1982 February 21 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Sermon "The Teaching Church" at Community Church, St. Petersburg Beach, Florida, 1982 March 14 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Sermon "Seeing and Not Seeing" at Sesquicentennial University Chapel, Miami University, 1982 May 2 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Taftville Congregational Church, United Church of Christ, Taftville, Connecticut, 1982 May 30 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - John Neumann Summer Institute, Waterford, Wisconsin, 1982 August 2-6 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Andover Newton Theological School 175th Anniversary Celebration Commemorative Service, 1982 October 18 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - The School of Theology for the Laity, 5th Series, 1981 September - 1982 May (Box 19, Folder 14)